JOSEPH SALVADOR

(717) 660-7535

1Salvador.Joseph@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/joseph-salvador/

Making the transition from management and customer service to Information Technology.

I have over ten years of experience of managing small teams of people with the main goal of ensuring the best consumer experience. Documented experience in soft skills such as Verbal Communication, Time Management, and Art Content Creation. Years of proven Troubleshooting experience and mentoring that could be an asset to your Vision

SKILLS

- Operations Generation of Profit & Loss Statements and Accountability to Corporate for the same. The hiring and training of new employees. Inventory Management Best Practices along with Reconciliation and Accounting
- <u>Vision</u> Created business plans by timeframe and training plans based on reports and employee interactions
- <u>Networking</u> Experienced in Locating, Inspecting, and Testing Wireless Mobile Networks, Mobile Internet Devices and
 E911
- Web Design Creation, maintenance, updating non-profit websites and associated web services
- <u>Computer Hardware</u> Familiar with Huawei, Alcatel, Cisco, IBM, Apple, and other common hardware deployed across networks such as Switches, Hubs, Routers, Fiber, etc
- <u>Computer Software</u> More than Proficient with Excel, Word, Datum, Ping, WireShark, Cisco, and other Major Software
 Vendors
- Programming Languages Python, CSS, HTML, JS,
- Known Environments Google Cloud Services, Amazon Web Services, OntraPort CMS, ZenDesk, Sumo, Google Ads, Youtube Channel Management, Amazon Ads, Adobe Creative Cloud

EDUCATION

Google IT Support Professional Certificate - April 2021

Coursework towards BA in Psychology - University of Maryland University College Maryland 2008-2009

Coursework towards BS in Information Technology - Kaplan 2012-2017

WORK EXPERIENCE

Social Media Manager / Higher Balance Institute / Santa Rosa, CA 08/2015 - 09/2016

Image and video manipulation, audio engineering. Maintained numerous social media platforms and business pages. Scheduling and moderation and formatting platform content.

Wireless Field Engineer / Metrico / Frederick, MD

02/2012 - 10/2013

Testing and developed tests for wireless networks. Tested unreleased mobile and tablets for functionality. Wi-fi hotspots through Fit4 Launch.

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Editor / Higher Balance Institute

01/2013 - Current

Moderated and edited transcription content for book publication. Auditing and providing summaries for online classes. Submitted artwork for promotional materials.

Web Maintenance / Eos Project

01/2012 - 10/2015

Submitted written content and maintained web pages.